ALEXANDER WILSON, PMP



Professional Summary

Dedicated and ambitious individual with a strong passion for cybersecurity with a background in computer science and project management.

A versatile and action-driven Project Manager with a track record of accomplishment in diverse areas. Experienced in managing risk, building stakeholder trust, and leading teams. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills. Background in incident response, network and software troubleshooting, and SharePoint administration. Highly motivated to learn more about networking, cybersecurity, and digital risk management.

Core Competencies

- Leadership
- Organization
- Adaptability

- Communication
- Planning
- Conflict Resolution

- Delegation
- Decision Making
- Budgeting

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AMEREN, St. LOUIS, MISSOURI, AUGUST 2019 TO PRESENT

IT Project Manager

- Lead and motivate multiple diverse cross-functional project teams of various sizes to achieve project success and align with strategic business goals such as workforce transformation and digitization.
- Plan, delegate, and drive critical project activities by tracking them in project information systems such as Oracle Primavera 6 or Microsoft Project and Microsoft Power BI reporting.
- Facilitate effective communication between project team members, stakeholders, vendors, and sponsors through project ceremonies via virtual and in-person communication methods.
- Review budgets, monitor project costs, and create financial forecasts using a variety of estimation techniques for projects ranging from \$200K to \$7.2M.
- Manage ongoing and iterative work by leveraging tailored Agile tools like Jira and Microsoft Planner.
- Record, collect, understand, and develop business, user, customer, regulatory/legal, and organizational requirements from a multitude of sources.

AMEREN, St. Louis, Missouri, May 2018 to August 2018, May 2019 to August 2019

SharePoint Development Intern

- Provided technical support to assigned business groups for SharePoint 2016 and SharePoint Online.
- Owned and automated the SharePoint site creation workflow by creating a request form, which upon approval would create the site and provision initial access using Power Automate ("Flow") and Active Directory Data Store.
- Migrated over 5,000 SharePoint 2016 sites to SharePoint Online, using Quest Metalogix.
- Created a workflow, to replace a "pen-and-paper" process, which enabled employees to digitally record pressure and temperature data at an Illinois natural gas storage station using only Microsoft Office 365 applications.
- Worked with multiple stakeholders to define and implement record retention policies, using Varonis
 Data Classification Engine, helping to ensure NERC CIP compliance for all newly created SharePoint
 sites.

ALEX WILSON Page 2

St. Louis Computer Services, St. Louis, Missouri, Part Time May 2015 to May 2018

IT Support Technician

 Provided remote technical assistance to customers, in response to incidents, by troubleshooting common Microsoft software issues and documenting/tracking them in Zendesk.

- Configured and troubleshot devices such as: routers, modems, wireless access points, desktops, laptops, tablets, phones, printers, and internet of things devices.
- Collaborated with team members to document and store technical procedures in a knowledge base (Notion) and continuously improve the information.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, AUGUST 2019

Missouri State University, Springfield, MO

MSU CNAS Undergraduate Computer Science Research Competition Winner - 2019

Topic: Automated Pathogen Detection and Quantization using Machine Learning

PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL (PMP), FEBRUARY 2024

Project Management Institute

NETWORK+, CURRENTLY PURSUING

Computing Technology Industry Association

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Proficiencies: Microsoft Office 365 Enterprise Suite (Teams, Outlook, SharePoint, Power Automate, Power BI, Project, Planner, Excel, PowerPoint, Word, OneDrive), Google Workspace Suite (Sheets, Slides, Gmail, Google Drive), Oracle Primavera 6, Trello, Jira, ServiceNow

Professional Organizations: International Project Management Association (August 2023 – Present), Project Management Institute (November 2023 – Present)

Personal Interests: Computers, reading, weightlifting, Yu-Gi-Oh, guitar, video games, travel, foreign language and food